piercecountylibrary.org 2008-09-30

# Pierce County Library > Web site Privacy Policy

## Web site Privacy Policy

#### Policy Statement

Pierce County Library System is strongly committed to protecting the privacy of its customers. The Library System believes that maintaining privacy on the Web is very important, and that informing its visitors about the types of information it collects and how the Library uses the information is crucial in the protection and privacy of our customers. 

#### Definitions

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small text file that is sent to your browser from a Web site and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies cannot read data from your hard disk or read cookie files that were created by other sites. 

#### Policy

**Type of Information Collected**

The Library does not collect any personally identifiable information. Personally identifiable information might be obtained from online transactions such as submissions, registrations, or donor pledges. Additionally, personally identifiable information may be transmitted through other activities, services, or resources made available on the Library’s Web site. 

Common with many Web sites, the Library's Web site automatically logs certain non-personally identifiable information about visits to its Web site. This information is used for system administration and for producing usage statistics.

 **How the Information Is Used**

Any personally identifiable information provided to the Library is maintained by and accessible only to the Library unless explicitly stated otherwise. The Library will not release information on customer use of specific Internet or Web site resources except as required by law.

 **Third-Party Partners**

The Library has partnered with reputable vendors to provide certain services to online customers. When customers visit a partner’s site, they are encouraged to become familiar with the other site’s privacy statement.

 **Security**

The Library has implemented all reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial measures to prevent unauthorized access to the information it collects online. The Library does not, however, claim any responsibility for information collected by other Web sites linking to or from the Library's Web site.

 **Cookies**

Examples in which the Library might use cookies would be to customize content areas; to analyze site activity or user behavior; or to maintain the state of authentication for member privileged pages during a given session.

If you are concerned about the use of cookies, please explore your browser's options to notify you whenever a cookie is set, or disallow cookies altogether. However, prohibiting cookies may restrict your access to certain Web content or features.

 **Promotional E-mail, Newsletter, and E-News Policy and Opt-In/Opt-Out Elections**

The Library may use personally identifiable information to contact you for promotional purposes. For example, on occasion the Library may wish to send e-mails to inform you of new exhibitions or other events the Library deems may be of interest. You will not receive such communications unless you have willingly provided your personal contact information.

**Policy Changes**

The Library reserves the right to amend this Web site Privacy Policy. Visitors to the Library's Web site are encouraged to periodically check this policy for current Library privacy guidelines.

 **Acceptance of Terms**

By using the Library's Web site, you signify your acceptance of this Web site Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use the Library’s Web site. Your continued use of this Web site following any changes to these terms will indicate your acceptance of those amendments.

**Reference to related Policies**

Internet Use Policy 2.11  
Confidentiality of Library Records and Patron Files 1.9

#### Last Revision

October 11, 2007
